Guide to the Sydney Ahlstrom Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, Series III
  - Forewords and Introductions
    - Religion and the Dilemmas of Nationhood, The Cosmic God, The New Era, or The Coming Kingdom, Philosophy and Christianity, Philosophy of Theism, Progressive Religious Thought in America, The Vicarious Sacrifice, untitled, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 210)
    - The Impact of American Religious Liberalism, The Rise of Modern Religious Ideas in America, Paper by David O'Brien, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 211)
  - Letters to the Editor
    - The Lutheran Companion, 1958 Sep 10 (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - Signs and Times, 1962 Dec 13 (Box 17, Folder 212)
  - Book Reviews
    - Reviews, 1950-1961 (Box 17, Folder 213-215)
    - Reviews, 1962-1981, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 216-221)
  - Booklength Works
    - American Protestantism (published?), 1961 (Box 19, Folder 222-223)
    - The Christian Unitarian Mind, drafts, notes (Box 19, Folder 224-235)
    - The Christian Unitarian Mind, notes, correspondence with publishers, 1953-1960, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 236-242)
    - Contemporary Theology (proposed), 1955? (Box 20, Folder 243)
    - Crown Pictorial History, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 244-245)
    - Francis Ellingwood Abbott: His Education and Active Career, drafts, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 246-249)
    - Francis Ellingwood Abbott: His Education and Active Career, drafts, notes, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 250-261)
    - The Puritan Spirit and American Life, drafts, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - The Puritan Spirit and American Life, drafts, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 263-269)
    - A Religious History of the American People, Vols. 1 2, 1975 Edition (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - A Religious History of the American People, draft of chapters 1-10, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 271)
    - A Religious History of the American People, draft of chapters 11-51, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 272-280)
    - A Religious History of the American People, draft of chapters 52-63, footnotes, drawings, outline, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 281-289)
    - A Religious History of the American People, correspondence with publisher, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 290-291)
    - A Religious History of the American People, correspondence with publisher, 1973-1978, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 292-294)
    - A Religious History of the American People, book reviews, 1972-1981 (Box 25, Folder 295-303)
    - A Religious History of the American People, book reviews, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 304-305)
    - A Religious History of the American People, related material including the 1973 National Book Award, 1972-1982, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 306-315)
    - Theology in America: The Major Protestant Voices from Puritanism to Neo-Orthodoxy, notes, correspondence with publishers, 1963-1968 (Box 26, Folder 316-318)
- Course Related Material, Series IV
  The material in this series is arranged alphabetically by title of course with the contents (ie. syllabi, exams, lecture notes, course evaluations) noted.
  - American Church History from Edwards to the Antebellum, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 319)
  - American Church History Survey Course (syllabi and exams), 1955-1976, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 320-327)
  - American Church History Survey Course (lecture notes), 1957-1971 (Box 27, Folder 328-332)
  - American Church History Survey Course (lecture notes), 1972-1983, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 333-346)
  - American Church History Survey Course (lecture notes), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 347-354)
  - American Church History Survey Course (course evaluations), 1971-1978 (Box 29, Folder 355-356)
  - American Intellectual History (syllabi), 1962-1979, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 357)
  - American Religious Conservatism (syllabi), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 358)
  - American Religious History: Problems and Controversies (syllabi) (Box 29, Folder 358)
  - American Religious Liberalism (syllabi and exams) (Box 29, Folder 359)
  - American Religious Thought: The Major Thinkers from Jonathan Edwards to H. Richard Niebuhr (syllabi and exams), 1974, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 360)
  - The Church and the Ministry (notes taken by student Kenneth E. Rowe), 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 360a)
  - Church Polity (syllabi and exams), 1957-1970 (Box 30, Folder 361)
  - History of American Religion and Its Socio-Political Impact (syllabi) (Box 30, Folder 362)
  - History of Rome (lecture notes), 1947 (Box 30, Folder 363-367)
  - Humanities (lecture notes), 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 368-369)
  - Ideology and Dissent in the American Tradition (syllabi, exams, and lecture notes), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 370-373)
  - Jonathan Edwards Seminar (reading lists), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 374)
  - Nathaniel William Taylor Seminar (syllabi and lecture notes) (Box 30, Folder 375)
  - New England from Dwight to Emerson (syllabi and exams), 1961, 1963, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 376)
  - Rauschenbusch Lectures on Puritanism (lecture notes), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 377-378)
  - Renaissance and Reformation (lecture notes), 1952, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 379-380)
  - Romanticism (syllabi, exams, and lecture notes), 1971, 1976-1977, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 381-384)
  - Social Gospel Reading Course, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 385)
  - YMCA Course in Religion, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 385)
  - Miscellaneous Exams, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 386)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, 1946-1947, 1968, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 387-389)
- Collected Material, Series V
  The material in this series is arranged alphabetically by topic. In most cases the material is in chronological order within each topic. Some of the topical headings come directly from Ahlstrom's subject file. The two folders of newspaper clippings are a sampling of material clipped by Ahlstrom and cover a variety of subjects. Two subdivided categories of material follow the general alphabetical listing of topics. A section of collected essays and articles on History/Religion/ Education is arranged alphabetically by author. The final section "Antislavery/Racial Issues" is arranged chronologically.
  - General
    - Bicentennial, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 390-391)
    - Cults and New Religions, 1970-1979, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 392-394)
    - Ethnicity, 1967, 1972-1975, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 395)
    - Mary Baker Eddy, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 396)
    - JFK Campaign/Election (articles and correspondence), 1957, 1960-1961, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 397-399)
    - Lutheran, 1955-1977, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 400-402)
    - Lutheran, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 403)
    - Music, 1960, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 404)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1948-1980, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 405-406)
    - Periodicals: The American Benedictine Review, The American Historical Review, Christianity Today, 1960 Mar, 1976 Apr, 1976 Oct 22 (Box 33, Folder 407)
    - Periodicals: Daedalus, New Haven Advocate, Studies in Romanticism, 1967 Winter, 1975 Nov, 1971 Summer (Box 33, Folder 408)
    - Roman Catholicism, 1960-1964 (Box 33, Folder 409)
    - Student Strike and Protests at Yale, 1960, 1965-1970 (Box 33, Folder 410-414)
    - Student Strike and Protests at Yale, 1970, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 415-420)
  - History/Religion/Education
    - Authors:
    - Abelove, Henry; Abzug, Robert H.; Adams, Michael; Aiken, Henry D.; Alden, Jerome (Box 34, Folder 421)
    - Allshouse, Merle F.; Anthony, Dick; Armstrong, James (Box 34, Folder 422)
    - Baker, George; Barnes, Jack; Barr, Stringfellow; Barr, William Richard; Bernstien, Richard J.; Barrett, Lee; Biersdorf, John E.; Blank, Sarah; Blau, Joseph L. (Box 34, Folder 423)
    - Bloch, Ruth H.; Bloom, Harold; Bonhoeffer, Dietrich; Bowden, Henry Warner (Box 34, Folder 424)
    - Branson, Roy; Brauer, Jerald C.; Bremer, Francis J.; Brown, J. Douglas; Brumbaugh, Robert S.; Brumm, Ursula; Bryce-Laporte, R. S.; Burtenshaw, Claude J. (Box 34, Folder 425)
    - Calhoun, Robert; Care, Norman S.; Carpenter, Joel A.; Carpenter, M. F.; Carroll, John; Carter, Paul A. (Box 34, Folder 426)
    - Chamberlin, Mark A.; Clark, Ramsey; Clebsch, William A.; Cogley, John; Cohen, Mark; Commager, Henry Steele (Box 34, Folder 427)
    - Conant, James Bryant; Constantin, Charles C.; Coughlan, Neil; Cracraft, Jane; Cronon E. David (Box 35, Folder 428)
    - Dastin, Barry L.; Davis, David Brion; Delattre, Roland A. (Box 35, Folder 429)
    - Delattre, Roland A.; DePillis Mario S.; Diamon M. L.; Dirks, J. Edward; Dixon, John W. (Box 35, Folder 430)
    - Eismann, Bernard N. (Box 35, Folder 431)
    - Elshtain, Jean Bethke; Elson, Edward L. R.; Elvee, Richard; Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 35, Folder 432)
    - Fendelman, Earl; Ferre, Frederick; Filson, Floyd V.; Ford, Franklin L.; Ford, Gerald R. (Box 35, Folder 433)
    - Foreman, Terry H.; Fousek, Marianka; Frantz, John B.; Frei, Hans W.; Frey, Betsy; Fulbright, J. William (Box 35, Folder 434)
    - Gallie, W. B.; Gardell, Peter (Box 35, Folder 435)
    - Gaustad, Edwin S.; Gay, Ruth Peter; Geertz, Clifford; Godbey, John C. (Box 35, Folder 436)
    - Goen, Clarence C.; Gottlieb, Gerald H.; Gould, Samuel B.; Graebner, Norman A.; Grier, Edward F. (Box 35, Folder 437)
    - Gustafson, James M. (Box 36, Folder 438)
    - Hamre, James; Harrison, John F. C.; Harrison, Paul; Hartt, J. N.; Hatch, Nathan O.; Hawes, Richard M. (Box 36, Folder 439)
    - Healey, Robert M.; Heilbroner, Robert L.; Henry, Kenneth; Henry, Patrick; Higgins, George G. (Box 36, Folder 440)
    - Hitchcock, Ethan Allen (Box 36, Folder 441)
    - Hitchcock, Ethan Allen (Box 36, Folder 442)
    - Hodgkinson, Harold L.; Hoffman, Stanley; Holbrook, Clyde A. (Box 36, Folder 443)
    - Holifield, E. Brooks; Holmes, David; Holmes, Arthur; Hunt, Erling M.;Hutchins, Robert M.; Hutchison, William R. (Box 36, Folder 444)
    - Iggers, Georg G.; Ireland; Robert E.; Irving, William S.; Irwin, Joyce L. (Box 36, Folder 445)
    - Jennings, Francis; Jenson, Richard (Box 36, Folder 446)
    - Kamogawa, Takahiro; Keniston, Kenneth; Katigawa, Joseph M.; Koester, Helmut; Kuklick, Bruce (Box 36, Folder 447)
    - Landauer, Carl; Land, Paul H. D.; Lawrence, David Ernst; Lea, S.; Lewis, W. Arthur; Lincoln, Abraham; Lindbeck, George (Box 36, Folder 448)
    - Linder, Robert D.; Luedtke, Luther S.; Lynn, Robert Wood (Box 37, Folder 449)
    - MacCormac, Earl R.; Marty, Martin E. (Box 37, Folder 450)
    - May, Henry F.; McCormack, Clyde; McCutcheon, W. J.; McLoughlin, William G. (Box 37, Folder 451)
    - Mead, Edwin, D.; Mead, Sidney E.; Meier, Richard; Merrill, Charles; Miller, Perry G. E. (Box 37, Folder 452)
    - Miller, William Robert; Mills, Frederick V.; Moore, LeRoy; Moorehead, James H.; Morgan, Edmund S.; Morison, Samuel Eliot; Mulder, John M.; Muller, Dorothea R.; Musto, David F. (Box 37, Folder 453)
    - Napier, Davie; Nassikas, John; Neuhaus, Richard John; Neusner, Jacob; Niebuhr, H. Richard; Noll, Mark; Norton, Andrews; Nuechterlein, James A. (Box 37, Folder 454)
    - Olson, Richard E.; Osterle, Heinz D.; Outka, Gene;Oxtoby, Willard Gurdon (Box 37, Folder 455)
    - Panoch, James V.; Pearson, Norman Holmes; Pierson, George Wilson; Pattillo, Manning M. (Box 37, Folder 456)
    - Ribuffo, Leo P.; Rodgers, John; Roeber, Anthony Gregg; Rose, Annie (Box 37, Folder 457)
    - Sageser, David B.; Sandeen, Ernest R.; Sarna, Jonathan D.; Schafer, Thomas A.; Schell, Jonathan; Scott, Ray (Box 37, Folder 458)
    - Seaborg, Glenn T.; Shaull, Richard; Shaw, Steven; Sherrell, Richard E.; Sheen, Fulton J. (Box 37, Folder 459)
    - Siegman, Henry; Smith, Timothy L.; Smith, Wilson (Box 37, Folder 460)
    - Smylie, James H.; Solberg, Winton U.; Spaeth, Harold J. (Box 38, Folder 461)
    - Stein, Stephen J.; Stendahl, Krister; Stone, Lawrence; Sullivan, Thomas V.; Swierenga, Robert P. (Box 38, Folder 462)
    - Teahan John F.; Tillich, Paul; Tiryakian, Edward A.; Tulga, Chester E. (Box 38, Folder 463)
    - Vahanian, Gabriel; Gilkey, Langdon; Vikner, Filip; von Moschzisker, Michael (Box 38, Folder 464)
    - Waterman, Leroy; Weber, Donald; Wiley, David N.; Williams, Peter W. (Box 38, Folder 465)
    - Wilson, John F.;Wise, Isaac M.; Wright, Conrad (Box 38, Folder 466)
    - Zaretsky, Irving I. (Box 38, Folder 467)
    - Anonymous (Box 38, Folder 468-469)
  - Antislavery/Racial Issues
    - Including: "Christian Interpretations of the Civil War," by W. Clebsch; "Bishop Turner's African Dream," by E. Redkey; Text of Summary of Report by National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, 1961-1967 (Box 38, Folder 470)
    - Including: "The Methodist Schism of 1844 and the Popularization of Antislavery Sentiment," D. Mathews; "White Racism and Black 'Emancipation'," C. Vann Woodward; "Race, Values and American Unity," J. K. Morland, 1968-1969 Mar (Box 38, Folder 471)
    - Including: "The Emergence of Black Political Leadership During Reconstruction, 1865-1890," T. Holt; "Radicalism for Humanity, A Study of Lutheran Abolitionism," D. Strange; "The Road to the Top is Through Higher Education-Not Black Studies," W. A. Lewis, 1969 May-1970 (Box 38, Folder 472)
    - Including: "Uncle Remus and the Malevolent Rabbit," B. Wolfe; "Evangelicalism and 'Immediate Emancipation' in American Antislavery Thought," A. Loveland, 1978, 1981, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 473)
    - Including: "The Southern Ethic in a Puritan World," C. Vann Woodward; "Attitudes Toward the White Minority on a Black Southern Campus: 1966-1968," I. Melish; "Zeroing in on a Fugitive Figure: The First Negro in America," J. Mirsky, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 474)
- Biographical Documentation, Series VI
  The material in this series is arranged in chronological order with notable events listed on the folders. Photographs are integrated chronologically and noted on the folder.
  - Including: Gustavus material, 1931, 1941, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 475)
  - At Harvard, 1946, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 476)
  - Including: Fulbright in Strasbourg; YDS Talks; Sermons, 1950-1954 (Box 39, Folder 477)
  - YDS Arts Festival (panel moderator); New England Association for American Studies Meeting: The State of Religion in New England Villages, 1790-1830, 1955 Feb-Jun (Box 39, Folder 478)
  - YDS Arts Festival (panel moderator); New England Association for American Studies Meeting: The State of Religion in New England Villages, 1790-1830, 1955 Aug-Nov (Box 39, Folder 479)
  - Including: Lutheran Faculty Conference; Photographs, 1955 Nov (Box 39, Folder 480)
  - Franco-American Conference, 1956 Mar (Box 39, Folder 481)
  - Including: Franco-American Conference; YDS Talk, 1956 Apr-May (Box 39, Folder 482)
  - Including: Summer Course in American Studies, Stetson University, FL, 1956 Jun-Aug (Box 39, Folder 483)
  - Including: March of Faith Lecture Series, 1956 Sep-Nov (Box 39, Folder 484)
  - Including: A Tercentenary Retrospect on the Lutheran Church in American Culture, 1957 Feb, Jun (Box 40, Folder 485)
  - Including: Sermons, 1957 Jul (Box 40, Folder 486)
  - Including: American Society of Church History Program, 1957 Sep-Dec (Box 40, Folder 487)
  - Including: Conference on Christian Higher Education, 1958 Mar-Apr (Box 40, Folder 488)
  - Including: New England Lutheran Faculty Conference; YDS Talks, 1958 Sep-Dec (Box 40, Folder 489)
  - Including: Lutheran College Faculties, 1959 Jan, Oct (Box 40, Folder 490)
  - Including: Our Protestant Heritage Lectures; The New Pietism Lecture; Sophomore Night at Branford College, 1960 Jan-Sep (Box 40, Folder 491)
  - Including: Sermons; 20 Lutheran Scholars Back JFK, 1960 Oct-Nov (Box 40, Folder 492)
  - Including: Commencement Address: Parochial Theology in a Contemporary Mood, Augustana Theological Seminary, 1961 May, Jul (Box 40, Folder 493)
  - Including: Religion in America Lecture, Amherst College; Sermons, 1962 Jan-Apr (Box 41, Folder 494)
  - Including: Bethesda Library Project, 1961 Aug, Dec (Box 41, Folder 495)
  - Thomas Hooker Lecture: Thomas Hooker, Puritanism and Democratic Citizenship, 1962 May (Box 41, Folder 496-497)
  - Including: Brewer Lectures, Beloit College, WI, 1962 Oct (Box 41, Folder 498-499)
  - Including: Minister's Seminar: The Theology of H. Richard Niebuhr; Commencement Address; Sermons, 1963 Mar-Jun (Box 41, Folder 500)
  - Including: Sermons, 1963 Aug, Oct (Box 41, Folder 501)
  - National Study Conference on Church and State, 1964 Jan, Feb (Box 41, Folder 502-504)
  - Sabbatical in France, 1964 Apr-1965 Jun (Box 42, Folder 505-507)
  - Including: Sermons, 1965 Sep-Dec (Box 42, Folder 508)
  - Including: LCA Synod Convocation Lecture: The Puritan Age in America; Sermons, 1966 Jan-Sep (Box 42, Folder 509)
  - Including: LCA Synod Convocation Lecture: The Puritan Age in America; Sermons, 1966 Oct-Dec (Box 42, Folder 510)
  - Including: Convocation Lecture, Colgate Rochester Divinity School; Sermons, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 511)
  - Including: Convocation Lecture, Colgate Rochester Divinity School; Sermons, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 512)
  - Organization for American Historians Lecture: The Moral and Theological Revolution of the 1960s, 1969 Apr (Box 42, Folder 513)
  - Including: American History Association Meeting: Puritan Studies, Problems and Directions; Sermon, 1969 Sep-Dec (Box 42, Folder 514)
  - Fulbright in Germany, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 515)
  - Fulbright in Germany, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 516)
  - Including: Keynote Address: Tamkang American Studies Conference, 1972 Apr-Jul (Box 42, Folder 517)
  - Kyoto Summer Seminar in American Studies, Japan, 1972 Jul (Box 43, Folder 518)
  - International Congress of Learned Societies in the Field of Religion, Los Angeles, CA, 1972 Sep (Box 43, Folder 519)
  - Lectures: University of Iowa, 1971 Oct (Box 43, Folder 520)
  - Including: Crown Pictorial History; Yosemite National Park Lecture, 1973 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 521)
  - Including: ASCH: Institute of Early American History and Culture; Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Aspen, CO, 1973, Mar-May (Box 43, Folder 522)
  - Including: Colloquium on Ecumenical Dialogue, Minneapolis, MN; Woodid Wilson International Center for Scholars: Symposium on Growth as a Value in American Culture, 1973 Jun (Box 43, Folder 523)
  - American Studies for Teachers, University of South Carolina, 1973 Jun-Jul (Box 43, Folder 524)
  - Seminar on the Bicentennial, Bryn Mawr College, 1973 Nov (Box 43, Folder 525)
  - Religion in America Television Show, 1974 Jan (Box 43, Folder 526)
  - Including: Address to the Lutheran Education Conference of North America: What's Lutheran About Higher Education? -A Critique, 1974 Jan (Box 43, Folder 527)
  - Including: Address to the Lutheran Education Conference of North America: What's Lutheran About Higher Education? -A Critique, 1974 Apr (Box 43, Folder 528)
  - Including: Address to the Lutheran Education Conference of North America: What's Lutheran About Higher Education? -A Critique, 1974 May (Box 44, Folder 529)
  - American Jewish Historical Society, 1974 May (Box 44, Folder 530)
  - Aspen Institute, 1974 May (Box 44, Folder 531)
  - Lecture: On Lutheran Higher Education, Concordia College, 1974 Jun (Box 44, Folder 532)
  - Bicentennial Reflections for the LCA, 1974 Jul (Box 44, Folder 533)
  - Bicentennial Reflections for the LCA, 1974 Aug (Box 44, Folder 534)
  - Lecture: Theology in America, Wheaton College, 1974 Oct (Box 44, Folder 535)
  - Otis-Stone Lecture I, II, 1974 Nov (Box 44, Folder 536)
  - Including: Otis-Stone Lectures III, IV; Religion in America Seminar, Washington D.C.; Photographs, 1974 Nov-Dec (Box 44, Folder 537)
  - Including: Otis-Stone Lectures III, IV; Religion in America Seminar, Washington D.C.; Photographs, 1975 Jan-Mar (Box 44, Folder 538)
  - Including: Association of Yale Alumni Workshop; Lecture Series on the Bicentennial, Brandeis University, 1975 Apr (Box 44, Folder 539)
  - Including: New Haven Bicentennial Committee; Lecture, Trinity College, 1975 Apr (Box 44, Folder 540)
  - Including: Commencement Address, Upsala College; Australia, 1975 Jun-Jul (Box 45, Folder 541)
  - Australia and New Zealand Society for Theological Studies, 1975 Aug (Box 45, Folder 542)
  - Including: LCA Assembly Presentation; Stowe-Day Foundation, 1975 Oct (Box 45, Folder 543)
  - Society for the Scientific Study of Religion Session, Washington D.C., 1975 Oct (Box 45, Folder 544)
  - Including: Interfaith Bicentennial Project; Lecture, Princeton University; sermons, 1975 Nov-Dec (Box 45, Folder 545)
  - Including: Lecture: Bicentennial Look at Religious America, Emory University; Lecture: Land of the Pilgrim's Pride, Wesley Theological Seminary, Washington D.C., 1976 Jan (Box 45, Folder 546)
  - Including: TCU Minister's Week; Bicentennial Festival, Notre Dame, 1976 Feb-Mar (Box 45, Folder 547)
  - Lecture: The Making of a Redeemer Nation, Pomona College, 1976 Mar (Box 45, Folder 548-549)
  - Lecture: The Making of a Redeemer Nation, Pomona College, 1976 Apr (Box 45, Folder 550-551)
  - Lecture: Piety, Revolution and Nationhood, United Theological Seminary, 1976 Apr (Box 45, Folder 552)
  - Lecture: Piety, Revolution and Nationhood, United Theological Seminary, 1976 Apr (Box 46, Folder 553)
  - Including: Commencement Address, Susquehanna University, 1976 May (Box 46, Folder 554)
  - LCA Seminary Week: Dilemmas of Pluralism in America, 1976 May (Box 46, Folder 555)
  - LCA Convention, Boston, 1976 Jul (Box 46, Folder 556)
  - LCA Convention, Boston, 1976 Aug-Sep (Box 46, Folder 557)
  - LCA Convention, Boston, 1976 Oct (Box 46, Folder 558)
  - Including: Rockefeller Award, 1977 Jan-Feb (Box 46, Folder 559)
  - Including: Rockefeller Award, 1977 Mar-May (Box 46, Folder 560)
  - Lecture: American Religious Values and the Future of America, Villanova University, 1977 Jun (Box 46, Folder 561)
  - Lecture: American Religious Values and the Future of America, Villanova University, 1977 Jun-Jul (Box 46, Folder 562)
  - Itasca Seminar: The Value of Urban Life: Cities as if People Mattered, 1977 Oct (Box 47, Folder 563)
  - Including: Photographs, 1977 Dec (Box 47, Folder 564)
  - Including: Photographs, 1978 Jan (Box 47, Folder 565)
  - Including: Gnosticism at Yale, 1978 Feb-Mar (Box 47, Folder 566)
  - Including: Gnosticism at Yale, 1978 May (Box 47, Folder 567)
  - Including: Photographs, 1978 Aug-Oct (Box 47, Folder 568)
  - Including: Currie Lectures, Austin Theological Seminary, 1979 Jan (Box 47, Folder 569)
  - Including: Currie Lectures, Austin Theological Seminary, 1979 Feb-Apr (Box 47, Folder 570)
  - Including: Report to Rockefeller Foundation, 1979 Aug-Sep (Box 47, Folder 571)
  - Including: Itasca Seminar: The Nature of Leadership in a Changing Society, 1979 Sep (Box 47, Folder 572)
  - Including: Wheaton College Bible Seminar, 1979 Nov (Box 48, Folder 573)
  - Including: Wheaton College Bible Seminar, 1980 Feb (Box 48, Folder 574)
  - Including: Union Theological Seminary Doctoral Consultation, 1980 Sep (Box 48, Folder 575)
  - Including: Union Theological Seminary Doctoral Consultation, 1980 Oct-Nov (Box 48, Folder 576)
  - Beecher Lectures: The Preacher-Theologian in the American Puritan Tradition, Yale Divinity School, 1981 Feb (Box 48, Folder 577-578)
  - Beecher Lectures: The Preacher-Theologian in the American Puritan Tradition, Yale Divinity School, 1981 Feb-Apr (Box 48, Folder 579)
  - Including: Leave of Absence information, 1981-1982 (Box 48, Folder 580)
  - Including: Reflections article: In Memory of Sydney Ahlstrom, by George Lindbeck; Tribute to Sydney Ahlstrom, Journal of the New England Lutheran Historical Society, 1984, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 581)
  - Including: Photographs, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 582-583)
  - Haverford Lectures on Romanticism, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 584)
  - Richmond Lectures (Box 49, Folder 585-586)
  - Selected bibliography for the White House Library, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 587)
  - Including: Sermons, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 588)
  - Including: Sermons, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 589)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Bibliographies, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 590)
    - Curriculum Vitae, 1954-1965 (Box 49, Folder 591)
    - Curriculum Vitae, 1967-1979 (Box 49, Folder 592)
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 593)